knpuniversity.com 2019-05-13

# SymfonyCasts - PHP and Symfony Video Tutorial Screencasts

Effective Date: May 25, 2018

## What this policy covers

Your privacy is important to us, and so is being transparent about how we collect, use, and share information about you. This policy is intended to help you understand: 

  * What information we collect about you
  * How we use information we collect
  * How we share information we collect
  * How we store and secure information we collect
  * How to access and control your information
  * How we transfer information we collect internationally
  * Information on cookies
  * Other important privacy information

This Privacy Policy covers the information we collect about you when you use our products or services, or otherwise interact with SymfonyCasts. This policy also explains your choices about how we use information about you. Your choices include how you can object to certain uses of information about you and how you can access and update certain information about you. **If you do not agree with this policy, do not access or use our Services or interact with any other aspect of our business.**

When we refer to "SymfonyCasts," "we," or "us" in this policy, we mean KnpLabs US, LLC, which controls the information SymfonyCasts collects when you use the Services. SymfonyCasts offers subscription video tutorials, which teach you how to program using technologies like PHP and Symfony. 

## What we collect

We collect information about you when you provide it to us, when you use our Services, and when other sources provide it to us, as further described below.

### Information you provide to us

We collect information about you when you input it into the Services or otherwise provide it directly to us. 

#### Account and Profile Information:

We collect information about you when you register for an account, create or modify your profile, set preferences, sign-up for or make purchases through the Services. For example, you provide your contact information and, in some cases, billing information when you register for the Services. We keep track of your preferences when you select settings within the Services. 

#### Content you provide through our website:

The Services include our website which is owned and operated by us. We collect other content that you submit to the website. Examples of content we collect and store include: comments you post on the site, videos you have watched, courses you have completed, challenges you have attempted, teams you have been a part of. 

#### Information you provide through our support channels:

The Services also include customer support, where you may choose to submit information regarding a problem you are experiencing with a Service, or questions you have on our content. Whether you designate yourself as a technical contact, open a support ticket, speak to one of our representatives directly or otherwise engage with our support team, you will be asked to provide contact information, a summary of the problem you are experiencing, and any other documentation, screenshots or information that would be helpful in resolving the issue. 

#### Payment Information:

We collect certain payment and billing information when you register for certain paid Services. For example, we ask you to designate a billing representative, including name and contact information, upon registration. You might also provide payment information, such as payment card details, which we collect via secure payment processing services. 

### Information we collect automatically when you use the Services

We collect information about you when you use our Services, including browsing our website and taking certain actions within the Services.

#### Your use of the Services:

We keep track of certain information about you when you visit and interact with our Services. This information includes the features you use; courses, chapters, challenges and other links you click on; frequently used search terms; and how you interact with others on the Services. We also collect information about the teams you are invited to. 

#### Device and Connection Information:

We collect information about your computer, phone, tablet, or other devices you use to access the Services. This device information includes your connection type and settings when you access, update, or use our Services. We also collect information through your device about your operating system, browser type, IP address, URLs of referring/exit pages and device identifiers. We use your IP address and/or country preference in order to approximate your location to provide you with a better Service experience. How much of this information we collect depends on the type and settings of the device you use to access the Services. 

### Information we receive from other sources

We receive information about you from other Service users and from third party services.

#### Other users of the Services:

Other users of our Services may provide information about you when they submit content through the Services. For example, you may be invited by someone team or an enterprise or business account. 

#### Other services you link to your account:

We receive information about you when you link a third-party service with our Services. For example, if you create an account or log into the Services using your Github credentials, we receive your name and email address as permitted by your Github profile settings in order to authenticate you. The information we receive when you link our Services with a third-party service depends on the settings, permissions and privacy policy controlled by that third-party service. You should always check the privacy settings and notices in these third-party services to understand what data may be disclosed to us or shared with our Services. 

## How we use information we collect

How we use the information we collect depends in part on which Services you use, how you use them, and any preferences you have communicated to us. Below are the specific purposes for which we use the information we collect about you. 

#### To provide the Services and personalize your experience:

We use information about you to provide the Services to you, including to process transactions with you, authenticate you when you log in, provide customer support, and operate and maintain the Services. We may use your email domain to infer your affiliation with a particular organization or industry to personalize the content and experience you receive on our websites. 

#### For research and development:

We are always looking for ways to make our Services smarter, faster, secure, integrated and useful to you. We use collective learnings about how people use our Services and feedback provided directly to us to troubleshoot and to identify trends, usage, activity patterns and areas for integration and improvement of the Services. We also test and analyze certain new features with some users before rolling the feature out to all users. 

#### To communicate with you about the Services:

We use your contact information to send transactional communications via email and within the Services, including confirming your purchases, reminding you of subscription expirations, responding to your comments, questions and requests, providing customer support, and sending you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and administrative messages. We also provide tailored communications based on your activity and interactions with us. For example, certain actions you take in the Services may automatically trigger a feature. These communications are part of the Services and in most cases you cannot opt out of them. If an opt out is available, you will find that option within the communication itself or in your account settings. 

#### To market, promote, and drive engagement with the Services:

We use your contact information and information about how you use the Services to send promotional communications that may be of specific interest to you, including by email. These communications are aimed at driving engagement and maximizing what you get out of the Services, including information about new features, newsletters, and events we think may be of interest to you. We also communicate with you about new product offers, promotions and contests. You can control whether you receive these communications as described below under "Opt-out of communications." 

#### Customer support:

We use your information to resolve technical issues you encounter, to respond to your requests for assistance, and to repair and improve the Services. 

#### For safety and security:

We use information about you and your Service use to verify accounts and activity, to monitor suspicious or fraudulent activity and to identify violations of Service policies. 

#### To protect our legitimate business interests and legal rights:

Where required by law or where we believe it is necessary to protect our legal rights, interests and the interests of others, we use information about you in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory, and audit functions, and disclosures in connection with the acquisition, merger or sale of a business. 

#### With your consent:

We use information about you where you have given us consent to do so for a specific purpose not listed above. For example, we may publish testimonials or featured customer stories to promote the Services, with your permission. 

#### Legal bases for processing (for EEA users):

If you are an individual in the European Economic Area (EEA), we collect and process information about you only where we have legal bases for doing so under applicable EU laws. The legal bases depend on the Services you use and how you use them. This means we collect and use your information only where: 

  * We need it to provide you the Services, including to operate the Services, provide customer support and personalized features and to protect the safety and security of the Services;
  * It satisfies a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as for research and development, to market and promote the Services and to protect our legal rights and interests;
  * You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose; or
  * We need to process your data to comply with a legal obligation.

If you have consented to our use of information about you for a specific purpose, you have the right to change your mind at any time, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place. Where we are using your information because we or a third party (e.g. your employer) have a legitimate interest to do so, you have the right to object to that use though, in some cases, this may mean no longer using the Services. 

In an effort to provide you with a delightful experience on SymfonyCasts we share information through the Services and with certain third parties. We share information we collect about you in the ways discussed below, including in connection with possible business transfers, but we are not in the business of selling information about you to advertisers or other third parties. 

### Sharing with other Service users

When you use the Services, we share certain information about you with other Service users.

#### For collaboration:

You can post content, which may contain information about you. For example, when you comment on a course, tutorial video or blog post, we display your profile picture and name next to your comments so that other users understand who made the comment. Similarly, when you join a team, your name, profile picture and contact information and will be displayed in a list for other team members so they can find and interact with you. 

#### Managed accounts and administrators:

If you register or access the Services using an email address with a domain that is owned by your employer or organization, or associate that email address with your existing account and such organization wishes to establish a SymfonyCasts account, certain information about you including your name, profile picture, contact info, content, and account use may become accessible to that organization’s administrator and other SymfonyCasts service users. 

#### Community Forums:

Our websites offer publicly accessible blogs, forums, bug trackers, and wikis like Trello Community5 and Trello Inspiration.6 You should be aware that any information you provide in these websites - including profile information associated with the account you use to post the information - may be read, collected, and used by any member of the public who accesses websites. Your posts and certain profile information may remain even after you terminate your account. We urge you to consider the sensitivity of any information you input into these Services. To request removal of your information from publicly accessible websites operated by us, please contact us as provided below. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to and why. 

### Sharing with third parties

We share information with third parties that help us operate, provide, improve, integrate, customize, support and market our Services.

#### Service Providers:

We work with third-party service providers to provide website development, hosting, maintenance, backup, storage, virtual infrastructure, payment processing, analysis and other services for us, which may require them to access or use information about you. If a service provider needs to access information about you to perform services on our behalf, they do so under instruction from us, including abiding by policies and procedures designed to protect your information. 

#### Links to Third-Party Sites:

The Services may include links that direct you to other websites or services whose privacy practices may differ from ours. Your use of and any information you submit to any of those third-party sites is governed by their privacy policies, not this one. 

#### With your consent:

We share information about you with third parties when you give us consent to do so. For example, we often display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our public website. With your consent, we may post your name alongside the testimonial. 

#### Compliance with Enforcement Requests and Applicable Laws; Enforcement of Our Rights:

In exceptional circumstances, we may share information about you with a third party if we believe that sharing is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, including to meet national security requirements, (b) enforce our agreements, policies and terms of service, (c) protect the security or integrity of our products and services, (d) protect SymfonyCasts, our customers or the public from harm or illegal activities, or (e) respond to an emergency which we believe in good faith requires us to disclose information to assist in preventing the death or serious bodily injury of any person. 

### Sharing with affiliated companies

Business transfers: We may share or transfer information we collect under this privacy policy in connection with any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of the SymfonyCasts to another company. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on the Services if a transaction takes place, as well as any choices you may have regarding your information. 

## How we store and secure information we collect

### Information storage and security

We use data hosting service providers in the United States to host the information we collect, and we use technical measures to secure your data. While we implement safeguards designed to protect your information, no security system is impenetrable and due to the inherent nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that data, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, is absolutely safe from intrusion by others. We will respond to requests about this within a reasonable timeframe.

### How long we keep information

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information, as described in further detail below. After such time, we will either delete or anonymize your information.

#### Account information:

We retain your account information until you request to delete your account. We also retain some of your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to enforce our agreements, to support business operations and to continue to develop and improve our Services. Where we retain information for Service improvement and development, we take steps to eliminate information that directly identifies you, and we only use the information to uncover collective insights about the use of our Services, not to specifically analyze personal characteristics about you. 

#### Information you share on the Services:

If your account is inactive, some of your information and the content you have provided will remain in order to allow other users to make full use of the Services. For example, we continue to display comments and content you provided to courses, videos and blog posts. 

#### Managed accounts:

If the Services are made available to you through an organization (e.g., your employer), we retain your information as long as required by the administrator of your account. 

#### Marketing information:

If you have elected to receive marketing emails from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences unless you specifically ask us to delete such information. We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date such information was created. 

## How to access and control your information

You have certain choices available to you when it comes to your information. Below is a summary of those choices, how to exercise them and any limitations. We will respond to requests about this within a reasonable timeframe.

### Your Choices:

You have the right to request a copy of your information, to object to our use of your information (including for marketing purposes), to request the deletion or restriction of your information, or to request your information in a structured, electronic format. Below, we describe the tools and processes for making these requests. You can exercise some of the choices by logging into the Services and using settings available within the Services or your account. You may contact us at [privacy@symfonycasts.com](mailto:privacy@symfonycasts.com) to request assistance. 

Your request and choices may be limited in certain cases: for example, if fulfilling your request would reveal information about another person, or if you ask to delete information which we or your administrator are permitted by law or have compelling legitimate interests to keep. Where you have asked us to share data with third parties, you will need to contact those third-party service providers directly to have your information deleted or otherwise restricted. If you have unresolved concerns, you may have the right to complain to a data protection authority in the country where you live, where you work or where you feel your rights were infringed. 

### Access and update your information:

Our Services give you the ability to access and update certain information about you from within the Service. For example, you can access your profile information from your account. You can update your profile information within your profile settings. 

### Deactivate subscription:

You or an administrator can deactivate your access your SymfonyCasts subscription. If you can deactivate your own access, that setting is available to you in your account settings. Otherwise, please contact your administrator. If you are an administrator and are unable to deactivate an account through your administrator settings, please send us a contact message. Please be aware that deactivating your subscription does not delete your information or team your information remains in our system. For more information on how to delete your information, see below. 

### Delete your information:

At anytime you may send us a message at: [privacy@symfonycasts.com](mailto:privacy@symfonycasts.com) to request your personal data to be deleted. Please note, that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes, to complete transactions or to comply with our legal obligations. 

### Request that we stop using your information:

In some cases, you may ask us to stop accessing, storing, using and otherwise processing your information where you believe we don't have the appropriate rights to do so. For example, if you believe a Services account was created for you without your permission or you are no longer an active user, you can request that we delete your account as provided in this policy. Where you gave us consent to use your information for a limited purpose, you can contact us to withdraw that consent, but this will not affect any processing that has already taken place at the time. When you make such requests, we may need time to investigate and facilitate your request. If there is a delay or dispute as to whether we have the right to continue using your information, we will restrict any further use of your information until the request is honored or the dispute is resolved, provided your administrator does not object (where applicable). 

### Opt out of communications:

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from us by using the unsubscribe link within each email, updating your email preferences within your account settings, or by contacting us  to have your contact information removed from our promotional email list. Even after you opt out from receiving promotional messages from us, you will continue to receive transactional messages from us regarding our Services. 

### Send "Do Not Track" Signals:

Some browsers have incorporated "Do Not Track" (DNT) features that can send a signal to the websites you visit indicating you do not wish to be tracked. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret the DNT signal, our Services do not currently respond to browser DNT signals. You can use the range of other tools we provide to control data collection and use, including the ability to opt out of receiving marketing from us as described above. 

### Data portability:

Data portability is the ability to obtain some of your information in a format you can move from one service provider to another (for instance, when you transfer your mobile phone number to another carrier). Depending on the context, this applies to some of your information, but not to all of your information. Should you request it, we will provide you with an electronic file of your basic account information and your learning history. 

## How we transfer information we collect internationally

### International transfers of information we collect

We collect information globally and store that information in the United States. We transfer, process and store your information outside of your country of residence, to wherever we, SymfonyCasts or our third-party service providers operate for the purpose of providing you the Services. Whenever we transfer your information, we take steps to protect it.

## Cookies

We use various technologies to collect information when you access or use our Services, including placing a piece of code, commonly referred to as a “cookie,” or similar technology on your device. Cookies are small data files that are stored on your hard drive or in your device memory when you visit a website or view a message. Among other things, cookies support the integrity of our registration process, retain your preferences and account settings, and help evaluate and compile aggregated statistics about user activity. We will begin collecting information about you or from activity on devices you use as soon as you use our Services. By using our Services, you permit us to collect and use your information from activity on devices you use in accordance with this Privacy Notice. For more information and to learn how to block or delete cookies used in the Services, please see below. 

Certain cookies we use last only for the duration of your web or application session and expire when you close your browser or exit the application. Other cookies are used to remember you when you return to use the Services and, as such, will last longer. 

We may use cookies to: 

  * Remember that you have visited us or used the Services before. This allows us to identify the number of unique visitors we receive, so that we can provide enough capacity to accommodate all of our users. 
  * Customize elements of the promotional layout and/or content of our Services. 
  * Collect data about the way you interact with our Services (e.g., when you use certain features). 
  * Collect data to assess and improve our advertising campaigns, including sending information to our business partners. 
  * Allow our business partners (including third parties) to use these tracking technologies to track your behavior on our behalf on our Platform. 
  * Collect anonymous statistical information about how you use the Services (including the length of your web or application session) and the location from which you access the Services, so that we can improve the Services and learn which elements and functions of the Services are most popular with our users. 
  * Some of the cookies used in the Services are set by us, and others are set by third parties who deliver services on our behalf. 

Most web and mobile device browsers are set to automatically accept cookies by default. However, you can change your browser settings to prevent automatic acceptance of cookies, or to notify you each time a cookie is set. 

You also can learn more about cookies by visiting [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/), which includes additional useful information on cookies and how to block cookies on different types of browsers and mobile devices. Please note, however, that by blocking or deleting cookies used in the Services, you may not be able to take full advantage of the Services. 

## Other Important Privacy Information

### Notice to End Users

Our products are intended for both personal use and use by organizations. Where the Services are made available to you through an organization (e.g. your employer), that organization is the administrator of the Services and is responsible for the end-users over which it has control. If this is the case, please direct your data privacy questions to your administrator, as your use of the Services is subject to that organization's policies. We are not responsible for the privacy or security practices of an administrator's organization, which may be different than this policy. 

### Children

SymfonyCasts is not for use by children under the age of 16 years and SymfonyCasts does not knowingly collect, store, share or use the personal data of children under 16 years. If you are under the age of 16 years, please do not provide any personal data, even if prompted by the Sites to do so. If you are under the age of 16 years and you have provided personal data, please ask your parent(s) or guardian(s) to notify SymfonyCasts at: [privacy@symfonycasts.com](mailto:privacy@symfonycasts.com) and SymfonyCasts will delete all such personal data. 

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by adding a notice on the Services homepages, login screens, or by sending you an email notification. We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use the Services to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy. 

If you disagree with any changes to this privacy policy, you will need to stop using the Services and deactivate your account(s), as outlined above.

### Further Information

If you have any further questions regarding the data SymfonyCasts collects, or how we use it, then please feel free to contact us by email at: [privacy@symfonycasts.com](mailto:privacy@symfonycasts.com), or in writing at: 

SymfonyCasts   
38 Fulton St W   
suite 400   
Grand Rapids, MI 49503   
United States of America
